CURRICULUM VITAE

POPOVICI Gabriel Sorin

popovici.gabriel@gmail.com +44 7795 295 097

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW: More than 8 years as a successful and passionate professional software engineer, of which 2 years of work in the USA, profficient in using Java, C/C++, C# and JavaScript in civil aviation and transportation industry, oil and gas industry, medical industry, online e-commerce retail industry, public and governance sector, banking.

Industries/project-type: e-trading platforms for banking/finance industry, logistic hubs, airline booking engines, data processing using distributed computing, border management systems, passport issuing systems, vehicle registration systems, information portals, web e-commerce systems, e-banking, middleware inter-process communications artifacts.

EDUCATION

Diploma Engineer, University "POLITEHNICA" of Bucharest, Faculty of Automatic Control and Computers, 2001-2006, Bucharest, Romania.

HONORS

"Leonardo da Vinci" Mobility Programme RO/2006/PL97046/S "Modern techniques for automatic identification", Department of Computer Science, University of Turin, Italy, April-June 2007

IT CERTIFICATIONS

Sun Certified Business Component Developer Java EE Platform 5, CX 310-091, 2010, Sun Certified Developer for Java Web Services, CX – 310-220, 2008, Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java Platform, Enterprise Edition 5, 2008, Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform, Standard Edition 6.0, CX-310-065, 2008

EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Developer

Sep 2015 - present

Employer: JPMorgan Chase & Co UK, Investor Services, CIB, Prime Brokerage, 35 Waterloo St, Glasgow Technology Center G2 6HS, www.jpmorganchase.com

Responsibilities: participate in all phases of the software development life cycle: user requirements analysis, writing detailed designs, implementation, debugging and unit testing according to Agile methodologies in place, lead/train JPMC resources/Contractors

Projects: **GRIPS** – in-memory position management system using Pivotal Gemfire, **CFS** - Custody Fund Services using Global Portfolio Equity Swaps platform

Senior Java Software Engineer

Mar 2014 - Aug 2015

Employer: *COMPUTAS IT* Romanian subsidiary of foreign-owned systems integration and software development outsourcing company (2012 net sales in the range of millions of EUR, payroll less than 100), Bucharest, www.computas.ro

Responsibilities: participate in all phases of the software development life cycle: user requirements analysis, writing detailed designs, implementation, debugging and unit testing according to Agile methodologies in place.

Projects and tasks:

- Logistics hub: automated tracking of goods within the supply chain of onshore/offshore facilities of oil companies
- Architected and developed UI web application using XHTML, CSS, jQuery, XSL Transformations and Xpath; implemented REST-full services based on EPCIS EPC Information Services Standard and ISO 15926 industrial automation standards for: Cargo Containing Unit's, Organization, Hire, Journey, Leg, Observations, Documents, Events model; developed Templates, UI Components using SPARQL Web Pages for Legs, Journeys and Observations data models.

Technologies: javascript, jQuery, XSLT, XSD, XML, xHTML, Java 1.7, Apache Tomcat 7.x, Apache Maven 3.x, Apache CXF 2.7.x/ JAX-RS 2.0 - JSR 339, Google Guava, Apache Commons; Semantic: SPARQL, RDF/RDFS, SWP developed with TopBraid Composer Maestro Edition-IDE, TopBraid Live Enterprise Server, Oracle 12c with RDF support

Java Software Engineer

Aug 2013 - Feb 2014

Employer: KEBA Automation SRL, Romanian subsidiary of foreign-owned industrial, banking & energy automation company-Romanian subsidiary develops proprietary software for foreign company-manufacturer of automation equipment (2012 net sales lower than 10 Mil. EUR, payroll of less than 50 employees), Bucharest, www.keba.com

Projects and tasks: developed middle-ware software applications to be used with banking automation equipment. Performed detailed analysis of the incidents reported by customers, transactions reconcilement and application errors. Created bug reports based on reported incidents and applications log files. Developed proprietary communication protocol for banking terminals. Developed customized ATM transactions software for foreign and Romanian banks. Integrated 3rd party payment/money transfer systems-Western Union. Improved Maven build scripts for automatic deployment into several production environments.

Technologies used: Java 1.6, C# .Net 2.5, ActiveX, JavaScript, Bash shell scripting, Maven, Spring Core/MVC/ORM/JDBC/AOP/Security/JMS, Jasper Reports, Hibernate 3.x, Swing, Netbeans IDE, Netbean Visual Library API, JMS ActiveMQ, IBM MQ 6.x, Oracle, MySql, H2, Derby, Apache Commons, Google Guava, jUnit, dbUnit, EasyMock, Mockito, XStream, XML-Apis, JAXB, JAX-WS, SoapUI.

Freelance Java Software Engineer

Apr 2013 - Aug 2013

Contractors: Anritsu Srl, Italian subsidiary of foreign-owned measuring instrument manufacturer, Rome-Italy (project-based related to the engineering of measuring instruments proprietary software, 4-month project); Romanian systems integrator-one of Top 5 companies in segment (project-based work on a Client Relationship Management-CRM application for a major power utility company, 4-month project), Bucharest, www.anristsu.com

Tasks: performed reverse engineering work of the Hadoop version 1.x IPC low level protocol to C/C++, and integrated Hadoop into middleware MasterClaw engine; related to the CRM application: developed custom made modules of standardized files, designed portal user interface, integrated application with 3rd party SAP/Energy products. Published on Git-Hub for the open source community under https://github.com/popovici-gabriel/projects.git

Technologies: Java 1.7, JAXB, Oracle Server, SAP Java Connector 2.x, Hibernate 3.x, Spring MVC, Spring ORM, Spring JPA, Spring JDBC, Apache Wicket, Apache POI, Apache iText, Jasper Reports, Google Guava

Java Software Engineer

Dec 2011 - Feb 2013

Employer: Sabre Holdings, Airline Solutions US-based proprietary software development company-travel industry, USA-based job under H1B visa status

Responsibilities: Design, develop, integrate, unit test, code review software requirements according to Agile practices and methodologies in place

Projects and tasks: performed active software engineering role in the development of a complex on-line booking engine/e-commerce application.

Technologies: Java SE 1.6, Spring Core/WebFlow/ORM/JPA/JDBC, Apache CXF, jUnit, Apache Commons, Hibernate.

Software Engineer/Systems Administrator

Jan 2011 - Nov 2013

Employer: Z-Terra Inc. US-based proprietary software development company for the oil exploration and production industry, US-based job under H1B visa status, www.z-terra.com Tasks: provided technology support for employees and customers; managed small computer farm (50+ Unix/Linux systems) of high performance computer data centers; developed Z-Eos Seismic data inspection: GUI application viewer(2D) for seismic data.

Technologies: C/C++, Qt SDK, Qwt Project, Glib, lib PVM, cmake/qmake, Qt Creator, IDE, Eclipse CDT, SQLite, Stanford Exploration Lib - SEPLib.

Software Engineer

Nov 2007 - Dec 2011

Employer: Canadian Bank Note International Europe, Romanian subsidiary of one of the largest specialized foreign-owned printing companies world-wide, Bucharest (Romanian subsidiary develops specialized software applications for governments worldwide), www.cbnco.com

Projects: vehicle registration portal, driver license issuing system, passport issuing control systems, border management systems.

Tasks: implemented dynamic report generation using Apache POI, engineered change requests, improved error handling and logging mechanism, developed web application scheduler, developed centralized task scheduler mechanism using JAX-WS SOAP web services and java 1.5 concurrency API, engineering change requests, dynamic PDF generation, UI front end development.

Technologies: Microsoft Visual Studio 2005, Eclipse, Java 6, Hibernate, Crystal Reports, Apache XML-RPC, Servlet 2.4, Tomcat 6.x, Rhino, OpenSCDP, MFC, Apache Axis 1.4, Servlets 2.4, JSP 2.0, JSTL, Struts 1.3.10, Java Mail, Hibernate, Crystal Reports, Tomcat 5.x, Log4j, Ant, Java 5 SE, JSP/Servlets, JSTL, Javascript, iText, JAX-WS, Struts 1.2.9.

Internship - Junior Software Developer

Jun 2007 – Oct 2007

Employer: Reply IT, internship in Milan-Italy with an Italian software development firm **Projects:** on-line banking system

Tasks: developed rich graphical user interfaces for the online banking system

Technologies: Java SE 1.5, JSP 1.2, JSF Apache MyFaces, Ajax4JSF(RichFaces), Java Servlets 2.3

Junior Software Developer

Aug 2006 - May 2007

Employer: Canadian Bank Note International Europe, Romanian subsidiary of one of the largest specialized foreign-owned printing companies world-wide, Bucharest (Romanian subsidiary develops specialized software applications for governments worldwide) **Projects:** vehicle registration portal and vehicle technical inspection application

Tasks : web application development, bug fixing, unit testing Technologies: Java SE 1.5, Java Servlets/JSP, Struts 1.2.9, Hibernate, Javascript, jUn 5.x, Ant	it, Tomcat